<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syed Zainulabideen</title>
    <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Syed Zainulabideen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 09:25:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SOLID: Liskov Substitution Principle (LSP)</title>
      <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/solid-liskov-substitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 09:25:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/solid-liskov-substitution/</guid>
      <description>LSP states that objects of a superclass should be replaceable with objects of a subclass without affecting the correctness of the program.
Subclasses should preserve the core functionalities provided by the Super classes and should not override or change them. Also subclasses should adhere the rules or contracts defined by the Super classes like method signatures, preconditions, postconditions etc.
So let&amp;rsquo;s take an example to show how code can violate the LSP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLID - Open Close Principle (OCP)</title>
      <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/solid-open-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 09:36:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/solid-open-close/</guid>
      <description>OCP states that software entities (such as classes, modules, functions, etc.) should be open for extension but closed for modification. In simple words it means that once a entity is created and working as intended, its internal code should not be modified to add new features or behaviors.
So how can then we add features or update the functionalities? And the answer is by extending the existing entities with by Subclassing, Extensions or Protocols/Interfaces etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOLID - Single Responsibility Principle (SRP)</title>
      <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/solid-single-responsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 10:20:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/solid-single-responsibility/</guid>
      <description>SRP states that a class should have only one reason to change or only one responsibility. In other words, a class should have a single, well-defined purpose.
Let&amp;rsquo;s understand this concept with a quick example. Suppose we have a User class and also there are two functioanlities accociated with this class i.e. saveToDatabase and sendWelcomeEmail.
Now condier the below code snippet that&amp;rsquo;s without the usage of SRP principle. We embedded the two functionality right into the User class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Injection vs Dependency Inversion</title>
      <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/dependency-injection-vs-dependency-inversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 17:43:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/dependency-injection-vs-dependency-inversion/</guid>
      <description>Dependency injection and dependency inversion are two concepts used in software development to manage dependencies between different components of a system. While they are related, they have distinct purposes and approaches.
Dependency injection is a design pattern that allows components to be loosely coupled by providing their dependencies from external sources. In other words, instead of hardcoding dependencies within a component, the dependencies are passed to it from the outside. This promotes flexibility, modularity, and easier testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripe Reader M2 integration with iOS</title>
      <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/stripe-reader-m2-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:34:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/posts/stripe-reader-m2-ios/</guid>
      <description>Hey Readers, In this tutorial we are looking into the Integration of Stripe’s In-Person Payment using Stripe Reader M2. Below are the quick overview of steps, we will be following.
Steps Overview: Create Locations: To organize your readers, you need to create locations e.g. Every reader is linked to the specific location of your physical store location.
You can either create location using Stripe Dashboard or using the Terminal’s SDK by following here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syedzainulabideen.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
